How do you adjust your model pose to a T-pose?
Before doing a hanfu, I will adjust the model pose to a T-pose.
Why do I adjust it to a T-pose?
Because when we are doing a hanfu,
because our hanfu is an ancient type of clothing,
when we were in ancient China,
there was not much division in the style of clothing.
For example, the clothes we wear now are divided into many, many parts.
In ancient times, most of the time it was a whole large piece.
When you wear a large piece of clothing,
it will be more inconvenient to use the arrangement point to arrange it,
because you are directly a whole large piece.
And when we go to create these clothing versions,
it needs to be designed directly into a T-shape.
So we will change the model pose to a T-pose in advance.
It's Marvelous Descender.
You can see that after we change the default pose,
the default model pose,
this arrangement point will also make some changes.
And now I'm going to start making a top of our clothing.
For hanfu,
everyone must be doing it.
For example, in the CG industry and the game industry,
what is the version of clothing?
There may not be any concept.
Marvelous Designer is based on some 2D versions to be created.
So if you are doing hanfu,
you can effectively help us save a lot.
You can save a lot of time
for those who don't understand the version,
those who waste a lot of time.
Because in hanfu,
you can usually just use some simple square shapes,
or create a version with some arcs.
Then we start drawing this square shape,
and then draw it into a T-shape.
Because our ancient clothing,
you can imagine,
some scholars who read books,
they prefer to wear some cross-stitch inside.
As you can see,
although I'm using a female model here,
I'm still giving her the most internal lining,
which is cross-stitch.
It's because the theme of the clothing I made this time
is a famous woman from the Three Kingdoms period,
a woman with more cultural heritage.
So I didn't choose to give her
a more feminine lining.
Generally speaking,
in ancient times,
the more feminine lining,
she likes to use this kind of moxious one.
I'm using the cross-stitch one here.
Then we can sew these panels together.
Because sewing is more basic,
so I speed up the process.
That's it!
As you can see,
we've got our rainbow pattern on the upper part of the dress.
The back part looks like this.
I'll show you how to make a dress out of it.
You can put a penny on it.
Now,
we'll fold the fabric inwards.
The
beautiful.
This is a flower.
Okay.
This is the inner lining of the inside
Just like the cotton shirt you are wearing now
Of course you won't wear cotton shirts in summer
Then I chose an outline of our board
Then extend it
After extending it, I will use it as a collar
You can see that we are turning over now
Why? Because when you look at the simulation
You will find that between the board and the board
When the outer layer and the inner layer of our board
There will be a problem of penetration
This is because our clothing
There will be some conflicts between the grid between it
At this time, we can choose the outer board
Apply a layer to it
There is a layer in the attribute editor
We set the layer of the outer clothing as 1
Then the rest of our layer default is 0
At this time
Turn on the simulation
The clothing will automatically identify its layer
How to squeeze out the line
Select a line
Right-click to expand the outline of the board
You can squeeze out a face
Then after we squeeze out the face
The sewing line between the several faces
We will edit it
When I observe the side seam of this model clothing
You can see our collar here
It's a little bit too much
Then we can sew its side seam together
Let its collar have a feeling of sewing
Now you can see
The collar of the clothing we usually make
We are done now
Layer operation is in
I put this position on the mouse now
Simulation attribute
After you choose a board
There will be a layer
Good
I will use the inner line tool after I'm done
Let's draw the inner line we use to cut
Then select the right-click to cut the seam
Now you can see our 2D window
Our board
It will be separated into two separate boards
So we can do this
Different boards
This is a fabric application
We can apply different colors to them
Then I applied an end-to-end shrink to it
You can see
When I use the end-to-end shrink
This clothing will become a close-up clothing
Then I will freeze all the boards
After freezing these boards
Will be with us
It is equivalent to freezing in the 3D window
The subsequent simulation will no longer be with it
It is that it will not be able to drag them anymore
Then I made a belt
It's because my family is going to make it
The most inside of the skirt
Shirt
It's the same
The skirt board
It has a feature
That is to say
One of its boards
It will be faster than our belt
It will be wider
Longer
So I just drew two rectangular boards
Then adjust its length
Make this skirt look longer
After I adjusted it to the appropriate position
I zoomed it out again
You can see
When our skirt becomes longer
This belt
It will fall down automatically
At this time
In our attribute editor
There is a function
Called the stretch function
There is a stretch thinning function here
This function
It can keep our belt
In the current position
Okay
After I wear it
I checked it out
This inside of the skirt
Is it what I want?
This is the effect I want
After it's done
I'll re-model it
Then it's the same
Give it a shrink
Shrink our tail
Then freeze it
You can see
Now in my video
The effect of my model
It's all personal
There must be some
Some friends will ask
Then why do we want to
Make this costume very personal
That's because
When we make the costume very personal
You go to the outer layer of the costume
In addition to these
Clothes that have been shrinked
When it's on
It's not easy to conflict
And it's easier to wear
After you wear the outer layer
We put the inside of the board
Restored to the original
More wrinkles and more
When it's a complicated situation
It will be easier to simulate
After doing this
Its wrinkles are controllable
We can finally put it back
You can put it back
To the original state
Cloth design
Cloth this software
It's mainly for us
Cloth designer
It can be used
It can be imported or exported
2D version
Modeless designer
Mainly for our
It's used in the CG industry
It can't be exported
And imported
Cloth version
That is to say
There is no way to use it for production
After I'm done
I choose
Directly import a version
Like this version
I downloaded it directly on the Internet
OK
Then I use it
Use it as a 2D background
Add to
It's a sketch
Just a sketch of this
2D version
Stain
Then you can see that we are now in the new version can be directly in the 3D window to do the sewing
Then, our skirt is now over the length of the ground
So let's create some internal lines to fold this skirt up
Otherwise, it will have a conflict and collision with the ground, which will produce unstable factors
So we will directly create the internal line and use this tool in the screen
Fold arrangement tool to fold the bottom of our clothes
When we select the internal line of the clothes bottom line
Fold
You can see that the 3D window of this clothing will be folded up
Then turn on the simulation
You can see that the position of our fold will automatically make a fold
Can avoid a collision with the ground
Then I manually adjust its position
If the fold is not the correct position of this model
I can just make a shape
Then I can turn over the fold lines
At this point, you can see that I started to simulate again
Because when we deal with multiple layers of clothing
We must remember
In order to avoid the sequence of layers of clothing binding together
You have to simulate the pressure between the fabric and the fabric together too much
we need to simulate it with the corresponding layer
Okay, then I use the pin tool
to make a cross-section of our outfit
and then use the pin tool to pin them together
because I need to add a belt right away
to fix our cross-section
So I use the pin tool first
to see how much it has
and then I adjust it
The difference between the pin and the strip is that
the pin will always maintain its original state
but the pin tool
makes your whole outfit harder
For example, a fabric that was originally made of snow
you make it look like a leather
Imagine that
you go to knead
The snow is easy to knead
It's very soft
But you have to pull it
or the leather is completely different
The texture is completely different
Then I make a adjustment to its pin
You can see that after we use the pin tool
the two points on the outfit will be sewn together
This is why it is called the pin tool
This tool can usually be used to temporarily fix some of our outfits
Two points
For example, like the one on my picture
Like the one I showed you in this video
Sew the two points of our outfit together
Then I add a shrink to it
to make it a tight outfit
Then you can see that
the waist here is a tight state
At this time, if I create a belt for it
it will be easier to wrap it around from the outside
Otherwise, imagine that
if the inside of this board is very big
it is more difficult to fix it with a very small waist
You can pour Maya's role in
and then pour it out
Then it's the same
When I made this belt
I applied a layer to it
You can see that this belt will be fixed
to the outside of the outfit inside
Then I deleted the pin
because we don't need to use the pin anymore
After I finished this step
I will consider
what kind of elements I want to add to it
First of all
I think this sleeve is a little long
I will shorten it a little
Then I will use the round tool
to adjust the uneven part of my previous drawing
to make its curve a little softer
And then I will give it a small curve
To adjust it
I will move the long end of the sleeve
by
We can see that
I added one more line
in this part
After the end of the curve
I can adjust the length to match the length of the sleeve
And then I will use this tube
which is a little smaller than the previous one
It's not the same as the previous one
After I pinched it, it became a fabric with the same width as the 2D window, which is longer than the original one.
Then I drew some paintings along the version I found on the Internet.
A fan-shaped picture like this,
at the end you sew it to a paper line,
it will form a water wave-like hammer.
Here you can see
I used the function of adding a line to the inner line.
When you select two lines,
you can select this function by right-clicking.
You can see that at the same time in the 3D window,
a lot of inner lines will suddenly appear in the 2D window.
After that, we apply some folding angles to it,
so that the white paper can be folded up.
You can see the effect later.
Then we use the folding tool in the 2D window
to fold these inner lines.
Now you can see that these inner lines are red and green.
Then I will print it first.
You can see that it folds up faster.
Printing this function
when you fold some lines with angles,
or when it is this kind of folding effect,
it can help you to achieve the effect you want faster.
This is how it looks.
Now we can go to the next step.
In the 3D window,
you can see the model that we are currently in.
The model is called the simple-to-fill model,
which is the image of a simple-to-fill model.
Let's go to the next step.
You can see that the model is now in a 3D window.
We can see that the model is now in a 3D window.
The model is now in a 3D window.
Now you can see the result.
After we adjust the position of the model,
we can now mix the edge of the model
and the model to the belt.
Now you can see that both sides of the leaf are folded.
Now we can see that the fold is more obvious.
It's not like how we usually do the other side.
It doesn't matter.
We can delete this line at the back.
After we delete this line, we can see that we can have this kind of folded leaf edge.
Or some of the decorative effects.
Then you can see that I did some operations just now.
After I chose the template, I reduced the strength of the template.
You can see that we saw that it was very hard before.
But now it's more smooth.
You can set the thickness of the fabric in the scene.
You can choose our template and set the thickness of the fabric in the attribute editor.
Don't forget to open the 3D window.
Here you can open a thick texture surface.
Then you can show its thickness.
Then I activated the inner layer of the belt.
It also reduces the strength of the template.
Because I want to explain to you.
Sometimes our clothing,
you feel that the template is outside.
Why does it still look unstable?
It's because if the strength of the template inside is relatively low,
If the strength of the outer layer of the clothing is relatively high,
The length of the line of the grid is too long.
Then if the length of the line is too large,
You can imagine how you can put a template with only 10 grids.
Let it be wrapped all the time.
For example, there are 10,000 grids of the template.
It's not possible.
So here I reduce its particle strength.
Because I reduced the particle strength of the edge of the contract.
Similarly, I also set a layer for it.
So that the belt can come out.
For the outer clothing,
If you want to import Marvelous Designer,
I suggest that you can directly use UV to remove the plate.
But for UV, you must pay attention to the part that does not overlap.
Then I applied another fabric to this belt.
Because I think this belt,
Its wrinkle is too much.
Here I choose to apply a leather fabric to it.
Or we directly increase its bending strength.
After opening the simulation,
You can see that after we increase the bending strength,
This belt suddenly becomes very hard.
Then it's spread out.
There is no wrinkle.
Because bending strength is used to adjust the effect of this wrinkle.
The thickness of the belt will not be too thick.
But the thickness of this belt is too thin.
For example, if you wear clothes a lot in the current life,
In winter, wear it will be thicker.
In summer, wear it will be thinner.
Right?
Then I thought about it.
Some of you may think,
It's inconvenient to find those clothes online.
So I'll demonstrate for you.
Next, I will show you how to adjust the default costume in our software
And make some outer costumes
First of all, I imported a set of men's costumes
Then I deleted all these useless versions
Only left a large version of it
Because I want to make it an outer decoration
It's not a decoration
Anyway, you know that there are actually a lot of outer layers of Hanfu
It has many layers
I mainly think that the two layers don't look very good
Then I added another layer to it
Yes, I suggest that you still import MD
Don't import the one with thickness
Go to other 3D software
After I made some adjustments to his version
Because imagine
The sleeves of ordinary ancient people
They won't be the kind of sleeves that are very tight
The sleeves that stick to your body
So I just put his sleeves
The sleeve side is stretched
And I adjusted some of his shapes
You can adjust these shapes according to your own ideas
Here I want him to have one
The outer layer is like that
An outer robe-like effect
Then you can harden it
Add it is the same
We can expand the outer layer of the day
Then make some creations
Let this outer robe
Can be longer
A little bigger
Because everyone must have seen our promotional picture before
I want to give him a more atmospheric one
And then a bigger one
And then it's the same
Repeat this step again and again
The outer layer of the version expands
You can see that the skirt outside us will become a little bigger
You must say
Why the outer layer of the version expands
I can't expand it all at once
I started to expand little by little
a little bit a little bit of expansion why because you imagine I just in the process of expansion
we also see that our clothing in fact, there will be some penetration of the problem
so if you once too much expansion that there are too many places he will penetrate you are relatively difficult to deal with
so when we use MD to make clothes, we must remember that there is a trick is that you have to do slowly
little by little to do not immediately do the board very large or suddenly put this board it is very large expansion
to let him especially in this kind of place must be careful to deal with
and then I just used a tool, I'll go back to you to take a look at
here he will have a penetration of a problem, so no matter how I pull
it
does not
come out, so I used the choice of the same tool to choose this grid to drag it out
and then you can see you put this layer of grid drag out after this clothing will be very stable
it will no longer have the previous kind of very unstable you are very difficult to drag it out of that kind of feeling
so do a lot of layers of clothing that is
when a must remember that layer of clothing must be frozen because the frozen can help you effectively go here I turned over the car because I drew the wrong line must be frozen only frozen these boards he can help you to improve your computer some of the budget
when you import the board you remember to teach you a method anyway now this step is also the step that everyone knows
that is to say that you are in a external sample with him as a reference when one is to look at the model of the waist waist almost is more than one-third of the amount
is that you go to see the waist is the thinnest your model waist is the thinnest place and your clothes waist is the thinnest place as long as your model is a human shape your model if not a human shape can not model is not a human shape to change other ways to a little bit of adjustment if your model is a human shape then look at the thinnest place
is a dress put it in our model 2D window above the comparison at least to have one-third of the amount of waist here
you can not be a model or model I am then so I went to a fine just on a normal pair of pants and then his inner and outer layer and then out of the this one on this one out of the yin and yang
because like I mentioned before, when you do multi-layer clothing, you must be patient and you must get rid of the two adjacent panels for it and then simulate it
I recommend that when you are doing single-layer clothing or more complicated clothing, you can first use the GPU to wear it and then use the CPU to simulate it.
Because the GPU is still not stable, it is better to increase the conflict density to 3 or 4.
Then I adjusted the lower part of the waist.
During the adjustment process, I found that there seemed to be some penetrations inside, so I pulled it in and looked at it.
After looking at it, I reset the layer level.
When the UV model is inserted, it can be generated directly.
Then it's the same. Let's arrange this created square sleeve version.
Hanfu is actually not as difficult as you think.
Hanfu, you can see that its version is actually very simple.
It's not that kind of, oh, you have to draw a lot of hand.
Then there's a curve here, there's a curve there.
In fact, Hanfu, because of our...
At that time, everyone's aesthetic was still relatively grand.
So you can use a rectangular shape, a square shape, it's all fine.
In addition to this, I made the lotus leaf side.
Lotus leaf side, you can follow me, pause the video and draw it.
Then here, I think there's a little too much fold in the sleeve.
I thought about it later.
Hey, how do I adjust it so that it looks like there's not so much fold?
Then I made some adjustments to its version.
It's also a adjustment to its fabric.
I applied it to a harder fabric like my big, wide belt before.
Then I drew the
Then I used a sewing needle to stick the outer layer closer to it, because I was going to put the belt on the outside again.
When I kept adding these layers, I used this belt to secure the inner layer.
Because there are a lot of unstable places to prevent you from doing the outer layer later.
Then I set a layer for this belt, and let it come out.
I remember that I also turned over here.
I found it.
It seems to be the same.
Why is it always unstable?
Then I found that this belt is still unstable.
I think, oh, I understand.
When you first look at this layer, you will find that there is a black circle outside.
This black is the inner layer turned out.
Because our layers will identify the front of the fabric.
Sometimes it can't identify the inner layer of the fabric.
So I decided to sew the outer layer of the clothing first.
The inner layer of the fabric will dry out the outside if it is molded.
Then I sewed the outer layer.
It is comfortable.
It is overlapped.
If there is a gap, it is Okay.
No problem, it is okay.
I sewed the outer layer.
I sewed the bottom layer.
Good thing is that the outer layer of the fabric is not too deep.
I sewed the outer layer.
If the inner layer is balled up, the outer layer is not balled up.
So I sewed the outer layer.
Then it's still the same, I found that there is still a problem, it still can't be worn out
I found that the back layer was the problem
I decided to freeze them all at once and then re-arrange the outer layer
There is another one, if you find that the outer layer of this version has conflicts no matter how
Sometimes it's because this version is too small
A few days ago, when I was doing technical support for a friend, I found that his version was too small, very tight
Just like a person with a waist of 80 wears a waist of 40 clothes, it will be tight in the end
Then I re-monitored them
The function of making a rope, the rope itself can be pushed, the rope can be made with a small line
Then I want to add a collar to the outer layer of the robe, a relatively hard collar
It's the same, draw a rectangle first, then slowly adjust it to the normal look of those collars
Then I drew the shape of the top layer, I changed it to waist width
It's the same, draw a neckline, I know the size of the neckline is slightly bigger than the waist
Then I drew the back part of the body
So I can twist the choir
I'm going to fix the upper part of the body
I'm a little confused, but it's the same
Then I made the arm
Then cut off the interlock
One the sides
Then cut off the shoulder
Then I started to draw the inner line
Of course, there are some problems in the process, you can also teach me
Oh, I mentioned this, anyway, I'm drawing some lines now
I just want to add some points to it
I'm drawing our inner line
When doing the knot
Usually the knot is finished and the budget is solved
About this, there is a friction coefficient in the fabric
Friction coefficient
You adjust it a little higher, for example, adjust it to 30
Then the knot you made will not loosen anymore
Is the fabric of the knot
The software can be pasted
Yes, increase the friction coefficient
If you increase the friction coefficient, it will still be solved
It's hard for me to imagine because I rarely encounter this problem
I really can't, I usually use
Fix it with a fixed needle
It's easy to fix
OK, it's done
Then I'll make a shoulder pad for him
The fabric of this shoulder strap is also leather.
I used a fabric with a bending strength before.
After you improve the bending strength of a fabric,
for example, if you sew it on your shoulder as a shoulder strap,
it can stand up.
It will have a more solid effect.
You will see it when I change the model posture later.
Then I will adjust the effect of the shoulder strap inside.
I don't know.
I don't know if you can see my rendering picture.
How to deal with fabric disassembly is better.
Fabric disassembly is like what I just said.
You deal with it layer by layer.
After you deal with each layer,
first of all, you deal with the inner layer.
From the inside to the outside,
you have to make it shrink from the inside to the outside.
This is more intimate.
Then do the outer layer.
After doing the outer layer,
you freeze it,
and then do it.
No, just freeze the inner layer.
Then do the outer layer.
Like what I am doing now,
just do it little by little,
and then do the other two layers.
What else can make it stand up?
The angle of sewing.
Oh, I also turned a car here.
I found that when I simulated it,
they seemed to be unstable when simulated together.
Then I simulated the innermost layer separately,
Then I checked if it was unstable, and found that it was fine and could be simulated.
At this time, I will simulate this layer of sand on the outside.
After they are all stable, I made a layer of fabric for them.
In order to prevent, it is equivalent to double protection, I am afraid that it will have the problem of coming out again.
Insert the model as a component, because the component is not involved in our simulation calculation.
So it will have the problem of penetrating the fabric.
If you want it to have a collision with the clothing, you need to insert it as a virtual model.
I only changed the leather, I only changed the attribute of the fabric.
Then I put this whole thing.
This is a simulation of the clothing and the outer layer.
Then gradually reduce its rate from the inside to 100 from the previous 80.
Then it is the same.
As you can see.
In the outer layer of this layer.
After all these thoughts have been changed.
After changing back.
The whole clothing has its own slowly, slowly.
It has the effect of my painting and wearing.
So I put it on the present.
Long sleeves, there is less of such long sleeves.
I suggest that you can have a method.
You add the elastic to the suturing line.
Don't pick too much.
想让它添加到我们外面的这一根飘带上面,让它有一个垂缺的质感,因为一般古代人他都会配一些配玉嘛,我因为不太擅长做这种配玉,我就做了两个珠子。
然后接下去我就再做这个披薄,应该叫披薄吧,就是披在我们古代的女性,比如说穿飞子啊,或者有一定地位的人,她很喜欢披的一个东西。
对,披薄。
在B弯处加一些褶皱啊,一个是我们建议直接到褶皱里面去雕,就是我们的Sculpt模式里面去雕,还有一个就在那一块增加一些面料。
因为我们的模拟基本上都比较像接近于现实生活中的衣服嘛,如果你要更多的那些细节褶皱,一个是可以抽弹性。
可以看看我上一期的这个视频。
这个飞行员的那个服装,中间我有教过一部分怎么样去做一些很厚啊,或者说增加一些褶皱的效果,就是加一定的弹性。
一弯自然结算是会有出来的,你等一下,稍微等待一下,我换姿势之后就可以看到了。
这里呢,我就给我的这个披薄增加了一个缩率,让它缩起来。
但是我给披薄加了一个缩率,后续会跟大家有一个解释的。
这里我就给它加了两个假缝针,因为我希望它固定在这个B弯的位置。
我其实对这些汉服其实也不是很了解。
所以你可以看到我管外层啊什么之类的说法,都是说外层啊什么之类的说法,都是说外层啊什么之类的说法,都是说外层啊什么之类的说法。
哎呀,这个外面的衣服,我唯一知道的就是披薄。
模拟模式就是说你可以把服装拆解为几个构件,然后你可以把不一样的构件拼搭起来。
比如说你觉得,哎呀,我是个水袖,然后我另外一件衣服我想配个机袖,或者说我想配个大袖子,小袖子,就把这些袖子拆开来。
比如说你觉得,哎呀,我是个水袖,然后我另一件衣服我想配个机袖,或者是我想配个大袖子,小袖子,就把这些袖子拆开来。
或者是我想配个大袖子,小袖子,就把这些袖子,作为单独的一个板块进行使用。
这里我就在调整这个模特的姿势了。
我想让这个模特是那种双手就是有点靠在腰部之类的一个姿势。
然后我就单独保存了一下这个姿势。
之后,我重新模拟了一下这个模特的姿势。
Increase the friction coefficient of the P-Board
Now it's time to witness the miracle
I changed this posture
There is no light setting in the software
Not yet in other 3D software
The clothes in the library can be added by default
Now it's time to witness the miracle
I added a fixing pin on both sides
And then I changed the friction coefficient
You see, suddenly
There will be a lot of wrinkles on the P-Board
At this time, let's reduce its particle diameter
It's about 3.5 mm
The P-Board is now quite thin
Now we can adjust the friction coefficient
We can adjust the friction coefficient
So that the P-Board can be darker
It's about 3.5 mm
Now you can see the P-Board is really thin
The P-Board is much thinner
It's almost 3 mm
Now we can adjust the friction coefficient
To lower the P-Board
It's about 3 mm
The P-Board is really thin
The CPU and CPU MDs are too low for the GPU and CPU MDs.
After that, I drew the line and wanted to do the sewing for it.
MD8 is available.
Long press
the model button.
You can see the GPU and CPU model options.
This is the last rendering.
This is a thick outer layer of the suit.